and we are live hello
everyone and paula hey
hi everybody um i'm i'm
here with you from a
conference on requirement
engineering so it's
good to be back in the
old software development
world with all of you
Okay, so again, welcome
everyone to the office hour.
So this week, the student is
working on Assignment
5 and GPD 0.
As promised, GPD 0
is extremely simple,
just your product
and that's it.
and we have assignment
for flow today.
So supposedly what you see
is what you get for all
of the automatically created
assignment that includes
A3 and A4. What you see
should be what you get.
But later we will update
that on Canvas as well.
So now we can go to the first
question is the
office hour threat.
Is there a specific
format that we
should be using for
A5? The earlier lecture
has mentioned
something about one.
and then there is another
comment from students
saying in the instruction
there is a section
saying ready mark down
and you add the level
to break down requirements
and the text etc
for each of the requirements
you must copy the list
of requirements and add
explanations of each one of
them. I expect that we
should strictly have no
mission embedded mermaid
diagrams and neither system we
don't want to render
consistently on our platform.
So that is correct.
Firstly, yeah, there is not
necessarily any template
right now. Later on,
when we are working on
this project, there will be
templates that students
can download. For this
one we expect the uh the
markdown and if there is
any uh diagram just make
sure that that diagram
is rendered or exported
into jpeg and then the
macdow itself can reference
to to the uh to the
And also really important
is, well, again, read
on the assignment instruction,
but one of the item
of the assignment instruction
that gets students
have point deducted is
that the student forget
to have must copy the list
of the requirements and
add your explanation to
each of them. Again, make
sure that you copy the
requirement from that
assignment instruction to
your submission, to your
work, and then have that
submission there. Otherwise,
here, I just mark now
and then the correct.
Next question,
on group project assignment,
What happens when one
of the team members
withdraw from the course
after they are allocated
to the group project? What
is expected of the team
if the situation occurs?
So the team, by the way,
this is, we already have
this course for more than
10 years. And of course,
this happens, so we have
a protocol for that.
Our team originally, most
of the team originally
have four team members.
and if one of the
team members withdraws
from the course, then
three team members are
still a viable team.
If there are only
two team members,
then it is kind of
a handicap team.
And in that case,
please reach out to us on it.
And basically, we
have two options.
If it is early in
the group project,
we let the team decide
whether they want to
move forward with the
team of two members
only and have certain
expectations reduced.
That's one alternative.
The other alternative is
to merge with other teams
or to split the team
members and then put into
other teams with only
three members. So it makes
the team of four again.
However,
splitting the team
is less resort,
especially late in the
group project. So it
will depend on the
situation and the timeline.
If things happen,
just get in touch with
us via a discussion
and the instructional
team will discuss with
the team member to
see how we can accommodate
such situations.
Okay, let's go to
the next question.
Do we get in contact
with our group this week
or wait until next week?
Should that contact just
involve setting up a
meeting time for future
weeks for this initial
communication? Should we
email them directly via
provided details, use a
group announcement in
Canvas or something else?
First of all,
if you already see the
contact, because it has been
what um four four five days
now and gpd0 only close
next wednesday so there is
another there are another
like five days if you if
you want to make the early
contacts to free to but
if you make a contact and
don't get response don't be
alarmed because some students
may have to wait until
the we can do so as well.
So yes, you can
do it right now.
You can use any
available communication
channel that you
can think of. That
includes email,
private chat on it,
even Microsoft Teams
message just for the initial
contact. and then for
later, the team can agree
whatever channels that
the team wants to use.
And then there's a
follow-up question. I am
adding to this question
in the group project, are
we allowed to use any
communication channel to
communicate with each other?
I checked the syllabus.
Yes, I think I just
answered before. Yeah,
because this is
private communication
between team members,
it is your choice.
The instructional
team does not dictate
how the team
communicates privately.
What UML editor do you suggest
we use best for A5 and beyond?
I don't have any
recommendation, to be honest.
I think in the previous
Office Hour channel,
I think somebody mentioned
that, but for this,
I don't know whether,
Paula, you have any...
You know, I remember when
I was still writing paper
on design, some of the
PhD students I was working
with who was doing, they
were using DrawIO, but for
this purpose, right, it's,
there are some tools that
are more advanced, but
then they are not for free.
For the purpose of just
submitting something just
choose a tool that you find
comfortable to design with
because you're not going
to use it for doing any
operation or things like
that so to be honest now when
i have to write anything
uml kind of diagram for my
papers i use canva but it's
just to say that it really
um for the purpose of this
assignment you just need
to draw and so whatever you
feel comfortable to draw
in uh you don't you because
then there are other
tools that allow you to do
some check but then you it's
not worth for what you
have to do to pay the
subscription and i see there
is an hands-on and i think
we reminded it other time
it's not possible during the
office hour to ask live
question if you have question
while we are in the office
hour use the ad post
and we will read them during
the office hour we don't
have the possibility to
have you ask the question
live in the in the chat
because then thing ends on so
and also to make comments
so if you if any of you guys
wants to contribute and
say i'm using this tool you
you can still use the uh
the ad pass to do it okay
uh thank you paula so let's
go to the next question
For my understanding of
A5, we must have left a UML
design document and design
description document.
The UML design document
must be UML plus
diagram as specified
in the instructions.
For my understanding of
the design description
document, does it
basically need to be
a document where we
explain our rationale
of each component in
our UML plus diagram?
I try to not answer this in
so unfortunately I cannot
give a straight answer
for now because it might
constitute SF3 grading for this
so I would highly encourage
this student and all of
you to read the assignment
instruction again and just
follow the instruction.
Yeah, so unfortunately, I
cannot give the
straight answer.
That would be unfair
to other students who
don't watch this OH or
previous students from
the previous semester
when we basically give
partial answer to the
assignment already.
Next question. Will VS
Code help in writing design
description document?
The instruction specifies
that we must save this
document in MacDao format.
Will VS Code help in
writing design document?
Maybe.
I mean,
maybe what you need is
just any editor that help
you write MacDao. I know
that for some people,
they use Beam Emacs or even
just a plain text editor
because they know the
MacDow format in and out.
Maybe MacDow is,
this is the first
time you encounter
MacDow and you have,
and you need some help
to understand what
it means to be
formatting as a heading,
as a title,
bone italic, etc. then
yes, maybe you can use VHS
codes or some other editor
that have you read myself.
I just want to be
cautious that if
you use any IDE
or online editor,
make sure that you turn off
any and own AI assistant,
because that might
get you into the hot
water of plagiarism.
So just make sure that
you have no AI assistant
at all when working
on this assignment
or any assignment.
Just to be clear, because we
are talking about VS Code,
and I know that's the...
If I say, oh, yeah, you can
use VS Code, then it might
be misunderstood at all. He
means that we use anything
that this VS Code offers.
Next question. Lecture
P3L2 keeps things at high
level. Considering that,
I understand we don't
need to show in UML
diagram that weight factors
are defaulted to one
in comparison setting,
clearly indicating current
job when comparing job offers,
methods to save, cancel
job details, etc.
As a design decision,
we can leave that
for UI. Is that the
right expectation?
Maybe Paula, you can chime
in a little bit. because
um it's more about so after
we have the requirement
engineer already now we
have to like write down how
much details is not cmi
not too much detail in
certain yeah so i think
it's i i was looking at the
question i think it's a
little bit connected to a
question that arrived while
we were starting uh you know
like how do you decide
when to stop right you want
to be able that you cover
all your requirements but
you want to make sure
you're not overdoing it so
it's a trade-off between
completeness and complexity
and actually not even
complexity is not even the
right word i would say and
overcrowding so make sure
you have the main domain
classes your all your kid
attributes all the core
operations right you've wrote
all your requirements so
at the end of the day, you
need to be able to go back
and say, check, check,
like I'm making these
choices to make sure I'm
covering these requirements.
But then you are not going
down into details that are
not at this level in your
decision process. Some
UI behavior, some like a
button action, these are
all decisions for later
because they're not needed for
complete your requirements.
So So this is, it's
really, it's an important
moment because you have the
requirements for a reason
to guide you in advancing
in your project. So try
to make sure you balance
your decision. So you want
to make sure that when you
are moving towards your
UML diagrams, you're covering
all your requirements,
right? Because otherwise,
why did you have them?
but it's not a moment to
make some other decision
that come later because
they're not informed
by they might not be
informed by the requirements
you don't have the
information there yet
thank you paola next question
can you give gaden how
to decide which operations
belong to which to what classes
i will be confused on what
the entry point does as
compared to the operation
of individual class i think
paula you are also happy to
take this question as well
yeah so okay so what what
is what what was the class
uh so let's these are two
actually questions right so
the first one is where should
an operation go on uh an
operation goes to the class
that either owns the data
for that operation or is
responsible for the behavior
you need to think about that
like so for instance you
think about you know you
are describing a restaurant
or you know all the classes
needed to an online restaurant
and then you have a class
that is order so when
you are calculating you know
the operation of calculating
the total is the total for
that order the order is
the one that owns the data
so it's where the operation
belongs right I does it make
sense I mean I understand
that you know it depends
on it depends on the it
depends case by case but
really the general rule is that
who owns the data who owns
which class owns the the
behavior who is responsible for
this behavior that operation
described and this is
where the operation belongs
i want to say that i want to
also make a note here when
i'm responding right the
fact that these are rules
in which you need to make
a conscious decision and
evaluate case by case is the
reason why you are needed and
we cannot code this and
have a program doing it for
you because this is where
you take the responsibility
to decide where things
belong and what do i need and
this this comment applies also
to the answer i gave before
right when do i stop where
how i because these are
decisions that you are making
in in in the present of
all these requirements so
it's uh it's there is some
let's say so from a from
from a design decision that
there are some arbitrary
decision from a correctness
perspective some are wrong and
some are right not you know
if when i have less students
i always tell them uh
you know as you better do
your own mistake than do that
someone else may say because
with 20 people in front
of me it would be very
strange if to have exactly the
same solutions because we
can make different decisions
and but some are correct
and some are not and some
different one are correct so
it's it's a But the rule is
that somehow the general
rule is that if you have an
operation, who has the data
for making this operation
happen? And if you say, oh,
the data are a little bit
distributed, okay, who is
responsible for this behavior?
And that's the class where
the operation belongs.
Did I answer the question?
If students feel that
we haven't answered
the question or have a
follow-up, please feel
free to have comments
under that question.
So next question, I think
it's again for Paula and
related to what we already
discussed as well. How can we
determine whether we fully
satisfy own requirements
while also avoiding unnecessary
complexity in the number
of classes, attributes, and
their operations. Yeah, I
think I partially responded
to this before, right? So
again, think of this as
having a checklist in
front of you. So you have
all your requirements, you
want to make sure you
cover all of them. And
when you're seeing your
crowded extra information,
this is when you are
making decision too early
and you are increasing
the complexity unnecessary
um and i think i think i
was actually this is the
one i saw just before i
loved this so this is i
i think is the one i was
uh i wanted to mention
yeah okay so um are there
any aesthetics requirements
for the assignment or
project with the color
or display of the project
count for the grade.
So first of all, it's not like
we are in the beauty contest.
So the aesthetic does not
give you extra points.
And I mean,
if it is kind of
visually unappealing,
but on the requirement
is there, the user
experience or the user
journey is fine. that is
that users don't have
to tap 10 buttons just
to change one setting,
then it's fine as well.
In short,
aesthetics itself is
not a requirement, it's
just that the user
experience in general,
And remember, UX is
different from UI, right?
Some apps can be just simple.
I think one of the
popular examples
that people often
use is Craigslist.
So especially for people
in the US, Craigslist
has remained the same
user experience for
like 20 years, even
default.com, right now,
it is not as visually
a pure as any Web2,
Web3, etc., but the
experience is the same.
It is satisfied that the
user expectation, user
requirement, so people
will still use it despite
it less than average
visually attractiveness.
so next question are there
any TA chances for this
course for next semester
if so um are there any
requirements uh maybe paula
can chime in in this and i
will also have some um i don't
know do you know something
about our TA team that
i don't know okay no so
we uh as for now we have
for what i know we have a
functioning and full ta team
but things always change
and actually i want to say
i'm not that much so familiar
with the rules that the
university have because
as i say in my introduction
i'm permanent faculty at
kansas state so every
university has different kind
of rules i'm pretty sure
you need to pass this class
with an a i suppose but i
would imagine that you have
to be graduated at least
with a master's degree to be
a master da um but maybe
i'm wrong maybe i mean this
would be a rule like i
wouldn't make up what what is
that um of sufficient uh
what what is that in the
math sufficient and uh reads
but basically necessary
but not no no you what you
want to say is necessary but
not sufficient i'm sorry
i'm the daughter of two
mathematicians don't mess up
this piece exactly so that
there's a necessary and
there's uh sufficient so the
the necessary right now
is uh well technically um
the school technically the
well technically the school
does have some hard
requirement and some of the
requirement coming from our
courses so the hard requirement
from the institution is
that you must yourself have
work permit in the U.S.
and physically in the U.S.
that is nothing the course
can our course can and can
change um but then um but
then they they don't
necessarily require you to be
the student or graduated
uh from uh from from the
program or even took the
practice right so actually
okay let me ask you this
question do you have to have
a master's degree in your
end when you are no because
some of the some of the
current uh students only
have the bachelor they
attend this to get their
first master degree okay but
so okay let's make a decision
three year because
otherwise i want let's make
a decision three so okay
you have a master's degree
the different way in which
you have the sufficient
condition so you have a work
permit or you and you are a
resident in the united
states so even if you are a
citizen of the united states
but you now live abroad you
can't you need to be
living in the united states
correct okay done so the
location and the more work
requirement done so now you can
if you if you have if you're
already graduated and you
have the competencies then
you also qualify what does
a student what does a person
who is a student in this
program currently as to
have as a requirement to be
able to be eligible the the
institution does not have
any um any requirement as
far as i know uh as far the
current student um they can
be current online student
again given the physical
and then work requirement uh
they can be online student
they can be on campus
student um they they can be a
master on-campus student,
they can be a PhD candidate.
And then I understand
that in the past,
and I think in the
present as well,
some of the TA are PhD students
of the current instructor
or, well, within the
department, right? So sometimes
Paula or Alex help with
other professors to get
the TA teaching assistantship
for students as well.
So for that, yeah, there is
more like instructor
discretion.
So as long as the
person qualifies the
institutional requirement,
then it is more
like the instructor
of record discretion,
whether to hire the TA, right?
And right now, it's
kind of the policy,
thought policy or guideline
for specifically for CS
6300. grade that we usually
check when we when we
do meet more TA we take a
look at the past semester
performance of
students so not only
you have to have a
you have to have TA
so even more even more
than that you have
extra like final score
of 95 plus or something
and additionally um a6
because a6 is kind of the uh
discriminated assignments
right so we have a really
long tail score distribution
of a6 so if you uh face
a6 then it's even more
chance that that you send um
you can be contacted to
be a ta in this course um
and again can i say that
this is very reassure can i
say that this for the
student is very reassuring
because you know how good is
the quality of your tas yes
i just think as a student
i would feel very reassured
okay um and once you
know why we have some uh
candidates um already mentioned
may not be the students
who already took the class
and then get the best
score in the class. But for
example, PhD students of
instructors, so the instructor
knows them personally,
the work ethic and
the competency, so
students should be
assured as well.
So that is kind of the second
category that we usually
get as a TA. And then the
third category is sometimes
we see people with
exceptionally great profile,
for example,
engineering director
at Cisco or FAN,
and they still want
to be humble and help
out and learn from the
students and the TA.
Sometimes those are the
profile that we take as well,
even though they might
not have taken the form
yet. So those are the three
criteria that we look at
for the instructor and
instructional team to
determine whether we want
to take someone in as a TA.
Now, actually, getting back to
the institution requirements,
we do have certain
constraints. It's
not like we can
hire 100 or 500 TAs.
We have the institution
constraint that the number
of TAs is proportional
to the number of students
we have each semester. so
it's usually one i think
one ta per 50 students plus
one ta per 300 students
so it's more like at
first you have one ta per
50 and then if you have
uh 300 you may have some
coordinator ta so that's why
there's a there's a formula
right so right now i
think we have a team of
uh 20-ish something TAs and
the capacity set for TAs
6300 is around 1,000. So
we are about that cool.
But some TAs, well, we
have TAs who have been
with us for like eight
to 10 years already.
Some TAs, they are just PhD
students. And then after
they graduate from PhD,
they move on. So once in a
while, of course, we have the
need for more CIS as well.
And then as this,
as it's called CIS 6300,
become more popular,
more students get into the
wages, the wages get longer,
we might need to increase
the capacity as well. And
that is when we need more
CIS as well. So that's all
of the information that I
know and then I can share.
That being said, if
you are enthusiastic in
being a TA in helping
with the teaching staff,
you don't need to look
only in this course
with other courses as
well. And every semester,
those with the
GATEC email should
receive, especially
OMSTS students,
should receive email either
from Dr. David Joyner
or from HR asking whether
you are interested in
the TA. And then you will
just fill out the form.
And then the rest,
the HR team and the
instructional staff
will take care.
so it's a long answer to
that question hopefully it
is uh it is satisfactory
answer for for the students
okay um even after that long
answer we know no longer
have any questions so i
think it's a is a cue for us
but before we're leaving i
want but he was satisfied
because he said thank you so
it was listening so i think
it worked okay nice uh but
uh before we're leaving
um i would love to hear
from paula about the the
conference so i'm actually at
this very small meeting it's
a working group on requirements
engineering and it's
very intense everybody does
one hour presentation so
today i heard about the
requirements security
requirements into adaptive in
system that change right so
think about smart home right
your smart home these are
actually very interesting
system because they're also
not regulated because
you're in your house you can
do whatever you want and
including a lot of damage right
because you don't really
know what you're doing and
so they were explaining um
how you can design system
in a way that you um they
can adapt uh from when you
plug in new things and be
receptive for new errors
so this is the thing i've
heard another very interesting
set of topic i've been
hearing about is you know
how you add human value in
your development development
of your software right
because there are many things
that are your personal you
know there are things that
are needs and then there
are things that humans feel
as their own value so how
do you when when you decide
how to develop your software
how do you fight this
i've heard a lot about
privacy and i talk i know
i know i already said it
but i talk about my work
in on using lm to develop
a format specification
and it's been very funny
because it's a very
interactive kind of
worship right and so I put
the title on and and three
minutes into the talk
somebody say but do you
do we really need formal
specification now that
LLM can write it for us
yes because actually they're
not that very good at
doing it actually there has
been a very interesting study
that shows that even
interactive system right like
not fully automatic
translation of natural language
informal specification have
the best like of 50 percent
correctness that is really
a big chance right if you
think about specifying the
software on the plane you're
flying on uh and uh and
even the interactive one the
one in which you know like
the human can still say
something because there is
this laziness that it creates
in human right this condescending
behavior that we have
when we interact with
somebody that speaks very well
and so we do it LLMs. Even
the interactive one gives
us, in the best case scenario,
80% correctness, which
is like, yeah, maybe we
shouldn't. And so this was my
first question. I said, it
started very well. And so
the answer, we shouldn't let
LLM do it, but that was my
last slide. So now I have
one hour and you already
know the end, but it was
still very interesting. It's a
very interesting group of
people but yeah so privacy
security human factors um
formal requirements oh today
about something this is
my you might like the best
it's um it's an extension of
git lab and the idea was to
try to use issues in git
to you know to to create an
automatic traceability
with your requirements like
which issues are actually how
do you connect them to your
own requirements and then
when the person was doing
this talk because they did
an extension just before
gitlab became part of the
bigger projects they're behind
like 40 000 commits but so
this is going to be fun at
some point in life but we
were i was thinking because
there were a question and
i was thinking this could
be the beginning of a way
to reverse engineering the
process right very often
people don't actually have all
the requirements written
down so maybe you can use
the issues to build the
requirements you never had but
anyway this is very interesting
so the conference is
going well maybe you didn't
want me to talk for five
minutes about it but i did
it so requirements will pass
so i will i will talk last
i promise yeah okay right
uh nice and let me see i
think we don't have any other
question so yeah I
think we can for the day
the night
okay then thank you
very much everyone
have a good day and
we have last word
thank you for being
here and I will see
you next week I don't
never know when the
break is so I think
we'll see you next week
and if it's break
you'll find out online
have a good week bye Bye.